Haneul Yoo

Bongdam-eup, Hwaseong-si, Gyeonggi-do, Republic of Korea

📞 +82-10-5269-2387 | 🖂 haneul.yoo@kaist.ac.kr | 🏶 haneul-yoo.github.io | 🕠 haneul-yoo | **in** haneulyoo | 💆 HaneulYoo13

About __

Haneul Yoo is a Ph.D. student advised by Alice Oh in the School of Computing at KAIST. She will earn her M.S. degree in August and start her Ph.D. program in September. Her research interest primarily lies in the intersection of natural language processing and computational social science. In particular, she mainly works on (1) understanding historical documents in low-resource languages and (2) applying and utilizing NLP in language education. She believes there are still myriads of underrepresented languages in NLP, and our efforts on low-resource languages can build more culturally-diverse language models. She also believes language learners can contribute to NLP techniques and data and vice versa.

Education _

KAIST Daejeon, Korea

Ph.D. IN SCHOOL OF COMPUTING Sep 2022 - CURRENT

• Advisor: Alice Oh

KAIST Daejeon, Korea

M.S. IN SCHOOL OF COMPUTING Sep 2020 - Aug 2022

· Advisor: Alice Oh

Ajou University Suwon, Korea

B.S. Double Major in Computer Science and Engineering and Digital Media, Graduation with Honors

Mar 2017 - Aug 2020

• University of Wisconsin - Stout, WI, USA — Semester Abroad Winter 2018

Experience _____

LAMDA Lab Suwon, Korea

Mar 2020 - Aug 2020 RESEARCH INTERN

- Study of Deep Learning Model for Bio-signal (EEG) Analysis
- · Advisor: Jungryul Seo and Kyung-Ah Sohn

KEPRI Daejeon, Korea

Sep 2019 - Feb 2020 RESEARCH INTERN

- Development of application services utilizing electric used power data
- · Advisor: Moonsuk Choi

QLD, Australia **CSIRO**

RESEARCH INTERN Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

- Convolutional deep neural network for detecting cattle in images/videos
- Advisor: Brano Kusy

Indielist Suwon, Korea

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & CO-FOUNDER • Establishment of an independent music platform and development of iOS application services Jul 2018 - Jun 2019

Publications

Rethinking Annotation: Can Language Learners Contribute?

(under review)

HANEUL YOO, RIFKI AFINA PUTRI, CHANGYOON LEE, YOUNGIN LEE, SO-YEON AHN, DONGYEOP KANG AND ALICE OH

Translating Hanja Historical Documents to Understandable Korean and English

JUHEE SON, JIHO JIN, **HANEUL YOO**, JINYEONG BAK, KYUNGHYUN CHO, AND ALICE OH

EMMNLP Findings

Dec 2022

HUE: Pretrained Model and Dataset for Understanding Hanja Documents of Ancient Korea

HANEUL YOO, JIHO JIN, JUHEE SON, JINYEONG BAK, KYUNGHYUN CHO, AND ALICE OH

NAACL Findings Jul 2022

Knowledge-Enhanced Evidence Retrieval for Counterargument Generation

YOHAN JO, HANEUL YOO, JINYEONG BAK, ALICE OH, CHRIS REED, AND EDUARD HOVY

EMNLP Findings Nov 2021

Image-based Deep Learning Approach for EEG Signal Classification

HANEUL YOO, JUNGRYUL SEO, AND KYUNG-AH SOHN

KICS Summer Conference

Aug 2020

Mar 2020

Proposal and Simulation of Optimal Electric Vehicle Routing Algorithm

Moonsuk Choi, Inji Choi, Minhae Jang, and Haneul Yoo

KEPCO Journal

Talks and Teachings _____

TA KAIST SoC Colloquium (Fall 2021), Machine Learning (Spring 2021, Fall 2022)

Teacher Python at Suwon Information Science High School (Spring 2020), Java at Maetan High School (Spring 2019)

Academic Services

Volunteer FAccT (2022), COLING (2022) Reviewer NeurIPS (2021), EMNLP (2022)

Honors and Awards _____

KAIST Support Scholarship

KAIST

Aug 2020

Sep 2020 - Current

Graduation with Honors

Ajou University

SUMMA CUM LAUDE (1ST PLACE)

Outstanding Volunteer Award

Gyeonggi Volunteer Center Jun 2020

Special Prize

BIXPO 2019

Nov 2019

Excellence Award

KIPA

CREATIVE START-UP COMPETITION

Nov 2019

Academic Excellence Scholarship

Asan Foundation Mar 2017 - Aug 2020

Skills

Languages Python, JavaScript, C++, Java, Ruby, Swift

Frameworks PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, Docker, AWS, Django, Flask, Vue, React